Changing Lives
Emmanuel, viewers. I am Annette.
And my name is Chris.
Welcome once again to the program Changing Lives,
where we will take a deeper look into the lives of people
who have been touched by God Almighty through the ministry of Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Yes, indeed, we know that in life, experience is the best teacher.
And through these interviews, we gonna be guided in so many ways to learn some very valuable lessons of life,
to learn how people overcame their challenges, how they endured their pains,
and how at the end of the day they came out with a wonderful testimony to the glory of God.
Now, in today's program we shall be listening to Mrs Augustina Orakwe
and her husband Dr. Orakwe, a retired controller of prisons in the Nigerian Prison Services,
and doctor of Sociology.
Together they had some tough experiences in life, especially concerning some ups and downs
in their marital lives but through Christ they overcame even in the midst of that very difficult situation
through discovering Emmanuel TV.
And today we are gonna take an opportunity to listen to their experiences.
We believe that through the testimony of this family, you will discover how marital bliss can be restored
and repaired, when we anchor our hope on the foundation of Christ.
Hallelujah! So you are all very welcome in Jesus' name to this program - Changing Lives.
It's a great privilege to have you with us today.
And we would like to start with our mother first.
If you would you can just introduce yourself to us and the people beside you,
and just share your testimony to our viewers to the glory of God.
My name is Mrs Augustina Orakwe.
The man beside me is my husband Dr. Orakwe. My left hand side man is my junior brother Chima Ozorumba,
and the wife Joy Ozorumba.
The problem that brought us to the SCOAN - we had problems in our marriage.
Years ago a voice came to me, telling me: "I will scatter your marriage."
But I didn't know how, but as a child of God I prayed and I forgot about it.
When my husband came back home that day, I told him that I heard a voice today
and what the voice said.
We also prayed and we left the whole thing like that.
But after I heard that voice, problems started in the marriage.
We started experiencing things we have not been experiencing before -
lack of trust in the marriage, so many challenges. Even this family idol had brought problems
not only in my marriage, but in the marriages of my siblings,
bringing people down. My eldest brother is a Russian trained petrol chemical engineer -
but nothing to show for it because of the family idol.
Because the family idol - on that day I received this deliverance - spoke that it had destroyed everybody.
And it's true.
Before we came to the SCOAN, like I earlier said, we experienced a lot of problems.
They themselves were experiencing several problems in their homes.
We never knew that it was the family idol.
So these problems continued on and on.
As a child of God, I went to so many places, praying, looking for solution but all to no avail,
until we came to the SCOAN because of watching of Emmanuel TV which my husband discovered.
So we started watching it. When we saw what God is doing in the SCOAN through Senior Prophet T.B. Joshua,
we now realized that our problems can be faced.
So that was how we came to the SCOAN and I thank God for His intervention.
When we came here that day, they ministered the New Morning Water on me
and the Holy Spirit took over and the family idol, spiritual husband started to speak.
Can you just describe what you experienced,
when that New Morning Water was ministered to you at that moment?
When the New Morning Water was ministered on me, I didn't know what happened.
I started talking... Even now, I am still thinking of how I got that word - "family idol".
The thing just came and started talking: "I have destroyed everybody, I have destroyed this, that marriages."
And it is true - no steady marriages in my family. Problems here and there.
We didn't know that it was the family idol that brought all these problems.
But thank God for Senior Prophet T.B. Joshua who submitted himself for God to use.
Because without him submitting for God to use him to deliver people, a lot of people would have gone.
But thank God for him.
So it was when we came here, that we got solution and I know, because of that deliverance on that day -
in fact, my siblings started getting testimonies.
And since that day, everything, my marriage is like we just started again.
Praise God.
Changing Lives
Praise God. It was wonderful.
And Doctor Arakwe, if we can hear from you, please.
Emmanuel! (God With Us - Matthew 1:23). I am Dr. Ifediora Arakwe. I am retired Controller of Prisons
and I hold a doctorate degree in Sociology.
And I served the prison service in Nigeria for 34 years.
In the course of my career, especially in the last 16 years, I had the privilege of being engaged
in international correction activities that took me around the world.
Before now we didn't know about Emmanuel TV.
We never heard about it. The only thing we heard about Prophet T.B. Joshua was in 1996,
when some pastors made some caustic remarks about him.
And you know, like everything evil, it went into the memory and settled there.
But as I started travelling around the world...
I am very sorry, sir, can you explain to us, you say 'caustic remarks' - what do you mean?
In 1996, some pastors in Lagos here said that people should not listen to Prophet T.B. Joshua.
In fact, it was printed in magazines that he was patronizing mummy water spirits and all that stuff.
When you say this type of thing, it easily settles in people's memory.
So nobody knew about Emmanuel TV; nobody knew about him.
That caustic remark in 1996 almost made us think no more of T.B. Joshua
and so it continued like that.
Even when this crisis came into my marriage, we were born again, we were believers,
we had a nearly perfect marriage but this issue that came up, this demonic attack in the family
almost tore the family to shreds.
I think that what was keeping us was our Christian confession.
So it continued and continued and continued and we were praying.
I must confess that even here in Lagos in the last six years, we were always coming for night vigil
every last Friday of January after 30 days fasting and praying.
And so I didn't know about Emmanuel TV. I didn't know about the SCOAN.
Like I said, I was involved in corrections, both internationally and locally and in Africa.
So it took me around the world but I started getting to hear about Emmanuel TV as far back as 2012,
when on one of our conferences in Uganda, a cabinet minister asked me -
because I was always dressed as a Nigerian, dressed in caftan, wearing the cap.
If the weather was sub zero cold, I would still wear it, then I would use winter jacket to cover up.
But I would always wear that Nigerian outfit. So the guy asked me: "Are you from Nigeria?" I said: "Yes."
The first person he asked me about was: "What about Prophet T.B. Joshua?"
I said: "Who is he?"
He said: "The man of God in Nigeria. Do you know him?" I said, I didn't know him.
So he said: "Your life must be miserable."
- And he is government minister?
- Yes.
So he said: "We have been to Nigeria. We had problems, we came to Lagos.
We came to Lagos and the man prayed and you are telling me you don't know about him."
I went to Barbados in 2009.
Somebody asked me: "How is Prophet T.B.Joshua?" I just waived him aside.
I went to Mexico, they said: "Senor, Prophet T.B. Joshua?"
I went to Singapore: "Nigerian! How is Prophet T.B. Joshua?"
Nobody was asking me about President Obasanjo or Goodluck Jonathan!
When I now had this experience in Uganda and the man's comment was like a rebuke,
I went back to my hotel room and turned on television and started watching Emmanuel TV.
In 2014 in South Africa, I addressed a conference of African Ministers of Interior.
One day, one from Zambia, when he was giving me a promise that he would invite me to Zambia
to come and look at the prisons, and see the changes, he now told me: "What about Prophet T.B. Joshua?"
So I came back and I told her, I said...
When I went to the hotel, I tuned the televison station straight to Emmanuel TV and started watching.
I couldn't sleep.
Changing Lives
Can I just ask you - what first went through your heart, when you first switched on the TV and watched Emmanuel TV ?
Well, I wanted to find out what the world was telling me about.
And it was happening in my own country, and I was ignorant of it.
It made me look very illiterate. It made me look very unschooled.
It made me look very foolish that ministers of cabinet level, will be telling me about
Prophet T.B. Joshua in my own country and I was kind of saying - I don't know.
As a Sociologist at that level, I should know.
So when I came back, I started watching. I said: "Madam, something is happening and we are missing it."
She said: "What?" I said: "Look at the television."
So we saw deliverances.
I want to confess - that was when my heart became very bitter.
That was when I became pained. And even I will ask the Prophet to pray for me,
so that that bitterness will go away.
Because I felt that some people were deliberately tarnishing the man's image
so as to prevent Nigerians from getting the best spiritually and physically from the deliverance here.
So I felt, I want God to forgive me. I really was angry.
So you would agree, sir, that what a danger in ignorance.
That is why it's happening.
I was telling you about my sister in law who is in Ejigbo here - just 100 Naira bus away.
I had to drag her to this place because when I said: "Your husband has been out of job for eleven years
and you were told that it was an affliction.
And you stay there but just to come here, you say - they told you the man is... Well, come here."
I am glad she came and got the first New Morning Water testimony on Sunday.
And I don't think anyone can put her away from Emmanuel TV, from the SCOAN.
So that's my pain.
But from that 2014, when we started watching it steadily, I came to the conclusion that
whatever it was - I had physical problems, my heart and hypertension - it was there.
When we came here in March, I got Morning Water and I was ok.
And I told her we were going to come again.
When we came in March, the man of God didn't have time to touch people.
We collected the Morning Water and left. We had our testimony.
But we still wanted to come back. We wanted one on one.
So when we came this time, we didn't see him, we were disappointed,
although the New Morning Water was ministered.
Maybe, because of the disappointment, the faith did not click.
Then, she suggested and I agreed that we stay another extra week.
Then we fasted and prayed for three days before that Sunday. The only prayer point there was:
"May we see this man of God; may we have an encounter with him."
When we came to the church that day, there was ministration of the Morning Water
but there was general church service.
Then I think an announcement was made that they were going to minister New Morning Water,
after that we can go.
I was a little depressed and I told her. I said: "Since we have got the Morning Water,
maybe after this Morning Water let's go back to Abuja. We have exhausted our resources, let's go back".
But little did I know that the Morning Water that was coming that day was the new one that had power and potency.
The moment it was ministered onto her, she went into skyline.
I knew deep inside me that what was happening to my wife was spiritual.
She would offend me and I would tell her what she did, and she would say she didn't do it.
From my experience on Emmanuel TV and the people that had been previously delivered
I knew that deep inside me that what was wrong, was spiritual.
It was only the Morning Water that brought the confirmation
and I want to tell you that after that Sunday we are husband and wife again.
It is just like when it was at the beginning.
Glory be to God.
And the pain is that we didn't come earlier. And that's why I spoke.
And I am going to use this opportunity to speak again to tell - not the foreigners.
Because when the man of God went to Mexico, he was received presidentially.
He went to Paraguay, Uruguay, Botswana, Ecuador, Singapore, look at Indonesia.
That is almost 90% Muslim. Look at South Korea.
Everywhere he is received but in this country where he is domiciled, he is not acknowledged.
He is not acknowledged. It is a terrible thing.
And I want to address pastors. They say they are Christians but do not acknowledge
that this man has the grace of God to deliver and to save.
They should allow that he is not asking for their congregation.
He is not asking for their members.
They should please tell their churches the truth, so that the people who are suffering under various
yokes can come here and be delivered, they should not lie.
So many people out there are under that yoke like I was being told: "Don't go to T.B. Joshua.
He is this, he is that".
T.B. Joshua is a genuine man of God whom God is using in this generation to do impossible.
To deliver people and to save them by the power in that name.
And anybody that is preventing you from coming here to seek deliverance from spiritual,
from physical, from every other yoke is not helping your business line.
That is the advice I want to give to Nigerians.
And I am using this medium to let them know that they are suffering because of ignorance.
The Bible says: "My people perish because of lack of knowledge."
I have come here and the yoke that held my family and my extended family hostage has been broken.
And if I had come here five years ago, I wouldn't have ended my career the way I did.
I served the prisons for 34 years, I was stagnated for nine years.
At the beginning, I was stagnated for 12 years, I retired as a controller of prisons,
while people who were less gifted were promoted to Deputy Controller General.
And I know that by the grace of God, I contributed immensely to turning the face of Nigerian prisons
around, both within the country and internationally.
I didn't know it was this demonic force in my family.
I am telling you who are out there, who is there listening to me right now - come to... Not that there is no God,
there is God in all churches but grace is imparted upon several people according to their faith.
Here is a man given to us in this generation by God.
People are spending thousands, hundreds of thousands dollars to fly from other parts of country
to come and get what God has given us in Nigeria, and somebody is telling that it's not available.
Please, for Christ's sake, come and be baptized and be delivered. Praise God.
Changing Lives
We thank you, sir. We know that a lot of people have actually watched and seen the deliverance of Mrs Arakwe
and have actually commented and sent lots of emails concerning your testimony.
We would like to read a couple of questions that have been received,
so we basically have questions from some of our viewers,
we have time just to read perhaps one or two.
So we have one from Kelly from Australia and Kelly asks: "As a doctor of Sociology,
would you have considered your marital problems to be a spiritual issue?"
Well, as a Christian, Jesus - when He was asked about tax, He said - give what belongs to Caesar to Caesar,
and what belongs to God to God.
And I even read political economy.
In my doctorate dissertation I applied Maximin principles in solving social problems, but that is there.
But when it comes to spiritual work, I believe God. No academic consolation comes in,
not for one moment.
So you realize that despite your education, this was a spiritual issue
that required spiritual solution.
Jesus said - give that which belongs to Caesar to Caesar and that which belongs to God to God.
And that is where I stand.
My academic convictions, my academic profession can not...
The Bible says that God has chosen foolish things of this world to confound the wise.
If I apply academic wisdom in this matter, I will derail. I will just move 100 degrees off my target.
When you want to come, you come by faith and the faith that moves is the faith in Christ Jesus,
delivered unto us. Not the law - because if the law were to come in,
which is conterminous with academics, then Christ died in vain.
Wow, thank you.
And we have another question as well; this is from Mr Nigel who is actually in Holland, from Netherlands.
And he asked: "If this problem had not happened in your life and family,
do you think you still would have found out more about Prophet T.B. Joshua?"
Yes. Actually we came here because we had that problem but it took us time.
We got into this watching Emmanuel TV in 2014 and this is 2017.
We also had enough faith to believe the man of God, when he is praying
that we could lay hands on the television and get healed.
We only came here because we felt this thing was becoming an irritant.
It was making us look like we were no longer the Christians.
So we now came here, so that on this mount, we could drop everything and continue our work.
But it wouldn't have meant anything because when we got glued to that television
and the marvelous work God was doing here, there was nothing like going back.
There was no going back.
Changing Lives
So at this point we want to hear a few words from Mr Chima, which is the brother of Mrs Augustina.
So Chima, can we hear from you? I heard that you also have a great testimony concerning a breakthrough.
Emmanuel! (God with us - Matthew 1:23)
Thank you, my sister.
My name is Chima Ozerumba, a business man. I live in Abuja.
And the person beside is my wife Joy Chima Ozerumba.
We have been in this journey for so long.
It's just like when the Israelites were crossing the biblical Jordan - it wasn't an easy thing.
We have gone to so many pastors - they would even see your intestines but they didn't have solution.
They didn't have solution. But I thank God for Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Immediately my sister called me that I should come,
that she had that deliverance, a lot of things started happening.
A document I had been looking for, for two and half years - I said: "God."
The next thing I said, I heard an instate: "Go to your jeep."
I went to my jeep, opened the door - I saw the document there.
A lot of things have been unfolding themselves.
Because of this family idol we have suffered setback - even my brothers and sisters.
My sister said the actual thing but today we have reached our promised land.
All those contracts - people have been calling me concerning those documents they called me so many times -
if I want them to start it afresh. I said I had not done it, so that they could please do it.
I didn't know that it was the deliverance my sister had. All these things have started unfolding itself.
Thank God for Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Well, as Prophet T.B.Joshua says: "Whether we plant or water, in Christ we are a team."
So we believe that God has gifted pastors in different ways. We just give glory to God that it was when you came here,
that God really opened that door for breakthrough in your family,
in such a wonderful way. So lets just finally hear a word from our sister as well here.
What would you like to say about this breakthrough in the whole family?
Emmanuel! (God with us - Matthew 1:23)
We thank God for today.
I am Mrs Joy Chima Ozerumba.
And Augustina is my sister-in-law.
We thank God for the manifestation of the family idol. The family idol has dealt a great blow in that family.
It has killed his younger brother, his elderly sister. It has done a lot of harm.
No breakthrough. Even our son would do WAEC - no results.
They would seize it and he is very brilliant.
JAMB - they seized it.
The day my sister in-law called us, invited us to come,
that she manifested family idol, I brought his birth certificate, laid it on the floor.
The New Morning Water was sprinkled on it. The next day he got admission.
He is in school now. We have been fighting. We spend 500-600 thousand looking for schools for him.
We have started seeing a lot of breakthroughs.
I had a pain, a great pain at my spinal cord. I got that Morning Water.
The thing flew till today. I had a very big boil. I don't know where the boil came from.
My blood sugar was 401. When I came in contact with the New Morning Water, the thing came to 73.
I was not eating rice. I didn't eat anything - even no carbs in my diet.
But since we came, I have been swallowing rice; they were even shouting asking me what is this.
Thank God for the deliverance.
Glory be to God.
To change physically, spiritually and the marriage - in fact, every department of this family.
Glory be to God. So I think at this point, lets just hear a final word of advice
from our mother who was the one who actually received that deliverance from the New Morning Water,
that opened this wonderful door of breakthrough for the whole family.
So madam, to cap of everything. What is your advice to our viewers?
My word of advice to viewers all over the world is that when you have this kind
of problems, don't go away, don't run away from God, run to God.
Watch Emmanuel TV. It is the faith booster, that is what I call Emmanuel TV.
Because if you watch it, you will know that your solution must come in the SCOAN.
That's my advice to viewers all over the world.
Amen. Thank you so much to the family. And viewers, you heard it from our mother.
She said Emmanuel TV is faith booster. And we really believe your faith has been boosted,
has been lifted up by this wonderful testimony.
And you know, there are several important lessons of life to be learnt.
We know that in the Christian home, Christian home does not just happen -
it is built. A Christian home is like a high school of learning,
where so many truths about life are really learnt. And one of the lessons
that we really learnt from this experience is that personal fulfillments and improvements in life
come through the continual process of learning from both positive and negative experiences in life.
Yes, indeed, we all face spiritual entities that cause crisis in our marital life, our family
and our careers. And the tool for these spiritual entities is simply offense.
Yes, when we feell offended, we begin to use our tongue
out of bitterness, out of anger and hatred to split churches,
shatter marriages, crush close relationships and tear homes apart.
Yes, and we know the Bible says - God is actually the Owner, the Author, the Originator
of relationships. So since relationships begin with God
and then overflow to people, we can't just quit from relationships under any circumstance.
Unless God himself releases us because the beautiful thing about God is that
He can speak strength through weakness. He can speak strength to us through challenges,
through difficult circumstances, through all of these issues that arise in our marriage.
God can actually speak joy in the midst of sadness.
And in a Christian home, we know that there can be no agreements without disagreements.
So that disagreement will lead to a higher level of agreement in Christ.
Indeed, and also there can be no understanding without misunderstanding.
It might be that this program has gone a long way to let us know
that even if your marriage is on the verge of divorce, there is hope, and that hope is in Christ Jesus,
the Anchor of our souls. So viewers, we thank you for watching this program
Changing Lives. We believe that as you are watching you are learning some secret truths
that will be changing your life and changing your family's lives and all those around you.
God bless you. Thank you so much for watching us.
Until next time, on Changing Lives from me Annette and from me Chris.
God bless you. Good morning.
Changing Lives
TT Monica Asefa 17/09/18
RV: Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov